Lukas Foss Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Lukas Foss Papers circa 1926-2000 1936-1995
ML31.F68
Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009
approximately 5,000 items 39 containers 18.5 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lukas Foss was an American composer, conductor, pianist, and educator. The collection, which documents his life and career, consists of music holograph manuscript scores and parts, sketches, correspondence, business papers, programs, clippings, promotional materials, contracts, and financial documents.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Berio, Luciano, 1925-2003--Correspondence.; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990--Correspondence.; Boulez, Pierre, 1925- --Correspondence.; Cage, John--Correspondence.; Carter, Elliott, 1908- --Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990--Correspondence.; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965--Correspondence.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009--Archives.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009--Correspondence.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009--Criticism and interpretation.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009--Manuscripts.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009--Performances.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009. Selections.; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963--Correspondence.; Kagel, Mauricio--Correspondence.; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999--Correspondence.; Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992--Correspondence.; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985--Correspondence.; Penderecki, Krzysztof, 1933- --Correspondence.; Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1927-2007--Correspondence.; Stockhausen, Karlheinz, 1928-2007--Correspondence.; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971--Correspondence.; Takemitsu, Tōru--Correspondence.; Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001--Correspondence.
Organizations
American Symphony Orchestra (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Philharmonic Symphony Orchestra.; Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra.; Chicago Symphony Orchestra.; Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra.; Cleveland Orchestra.; Israel. Rashut ha-shidur. Tizmoret.; Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra.; Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra.; Tōkyō Firuhāmonī Kōkyō Gakudan.; Vancouver Symphony Orchestra.
Subjects
Composers--United States.; Conductors (Music)--United States.; Music teachers--United States.; Music--Manuscripts.; Pianists--United States.
Form/Genre
Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Programs (Documents); Promotional materials.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Purchase, Music Division, 2000.
Accruals
No further accruals expected.
Transfers
Sound recordings from the Lukas Foss Papers have been transferred to the Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division.
Related Material
The Library of Congress Music Division holds several collections that contain material related to Lukas Foss. The
USIA Artistic Ambassador Program Musical Commissions (ML31.U72)
contains a holograph manuscript of Foss' Central Park Reel. The
Louise Talma Papers (ML31.T34)
contain holograph manuscript scores for numerous Foss compositions, as well as correspondence from the composer. The following collections hold additional materials:
Leonard Bernstein Collection (ML31.B49)
Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection
Aaron Copland Collection (ML31.C7)
Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection (ML31.C78)
David Diamond Papers
Irving Fine Collection (ML31.F5)
Roy Harris Papers (ML31.H37)
Jascha Heifetz Collection (ML31.H4)
Serge Koussevitzky Archive (ML31.K66)
Boris Koutzen Collection (ML31.K68)
Nikolai Lopatnikoff Collection (ML31.L6)
Moldenhaur Archives at the Library of Congress (ML31.M6)
Artur Rodzinski Collection (ML31.R64)
and
Nicolas Slonimsky Collection (ML31.S6)
. In addition, the Marian MacDowell Papers in the Library of Congress Manuscript Division contain Foss correspondence.
Access and Restrictions
The Lukas Foss Papers are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1922, Aug. 15 Born, Berlin, Germany
1929 Began piano and theory lessons with Julius Goldstein Herford
1933 Moved with family to Paris to escape Nazi persecution Studied piano with Lazare Lévy, composition with Nöel Gallon, orchestration with Felix Wolfes, and flute with Louís Moyse at Lyceé Pasteur, Paris
1937 Moved to New York City Studied piano with Isabelle Vengerova, composition with Rosario Scalero, orchestration with Randall Thompson, and conducting with Fritz Reiner at the Curtis Institute Composed Four Two-Part Inventions and Grotesque Dance
1940-1943 Studied composition with Paul Hindemith and conducting with Serge Koussevitzky at the Berkshire Music Center
1942 Became an American citizen Composed The Prairie
1944-1950 Named official pianist of the Boston Symphony Orchestra
1945 Became youngest recipient of the Guggenheim Fellowship Composed Song of Songs
1946 Began teaching summer classes in composition at the Berkshire Music Center
1950 Received first Fulbright Scholarship
1951 Premiere of Concerto for Piano and Orchestra No. 2 in Venice, with Foss as soloist Married Cornelia Brendel
1953-1962 Professor of composition and conducting, University of California, Los Angeles
1955-1957 Directed the Ojai Festival in Japan
1957 Formed Improvisation Chamber Ensemble with Charles DeLancy and Richard Dufallo
1959-1960 Composed Time Cycle
1960 Directed the Ojai Festival in Japan Received second Guggenheim Fellowship
1961-1963 Composed Echoi
1962 Moved to Buffalo, New York
1962-1968 Conductor and music director for the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra
1963 Founded and co-directed with Allen Sapp the Center of Creative and Performing Arts at the State University of New York at Buffalo
1969 Composed Paradigm
1969-1971 Visiting professor, Harvard University
1970 Composed M.A.P. (Musicians at Play)
1971-1990 Conductor and music advisor of the Brooklyn Philharmonia
1972 Visiting professor, Manhattan School of Music
1972-1976 Conductor and music advisor of the Kol Israel Orchestra of Jerusalem
1975 Began residency at the University of Cincinatti Conservatory of Music
1981-1986 Music director of the Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra
1986 Composed Three American Pieces
1989 Composed Elegy for Anne Frank
1991 Professor, music theory and composition, Boston University
1993 Composed Left Hand Piano Concerto
1998 Composed String Quartet No. 4
2002 Composed Symphonic Fantasy for Orchestra
2009, Feb. 1 Died, New York City
Scope and Content Note
The Lukas Foss Papers span the period 1926 to 2000, with the majority of the materials dating from 1936 to 1995. The collection consists of holograph manuscript scores and parts, sketches, correspondence, business papers, programs, clippings, promotional materials, contracts, and financial documents.
The Music series documents Foss' lengthy and experimental career as a composer, beginning with early opera sketches and piano pieces written before his tenth birthday. Later compositions, especially those which reflect his interests in twelve-tone and aleatory music, are accompanied by extensive supplementary notes, tone rows, mathematical charts, and performance instructions. Photocopied scores and parts often include annotations by Foss or various conductors and performers. Notable holograph scores include Night Music for John Lennon, Elegy for Anne Frank, Renaissance Concerto, The Prairie: Symphonic Suite, Three Airs for Frank O'Hara's Angel, Echoi, M.A.P. (Musicians at Play), and Tashi. Works are arranged categorically by instrumentation and alphabetically by title therein.
The Correspondence series contains items to and from notable musical figures which are arranged alphabetically by last name. Included are letters from Luciano Berio, Leonard Bernstein, Pierre Boulez, John Cage, Elliott Carter, Aaron Copland, Henry Cowell, Paul Hindemith, Mauricio Kagel, Yehudi Menuhin, Olivier Messiaen, Eugene Ormandy, Krzysztof Penderecki, Mstislav Rostropovich, Karlheinz Stockhausen, Igor Stravinsky, Toru Takemitsu, Iannis Xenackis, and numerous other composers and performers. Correspondence with organizations and lesser known individuals is arranged by subject heading within the Business Papers series. These office files chiefly contain letters, programs, clippings, and legal or financial documents related to Foss' tenure with various orchestras in the United States and abroad, including the Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra, Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, Brooklyn Symphony Orchestra, Jerusalem Symphony Orchestra, Tokyo Philharmonic, Vancouver Symphony Orchestra, and the Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra.
Folders bearing general titles such as "England" or "Italy" contain assorted materials pertaining to the composer's conducting tours and side projects within these countries. Additional files consist of lecture notes and correspondence with universities, ideas for concert programming, writings by or about Foss, and miscellaneous documents for other topics of interest. The Musical Works Files series contains Foss' extensive file of correspondence, clippings, notes, programs, and promotional items related to specific musical works. These are arranged by title of composition and provide excellent contextual materials for research in musical analysis and performance history. The remaining collection materials can be found in the Miscellany series and consist of programs, articles, and a single writing by Louise Talma.
Organization of the Lukas Foss Papers
The Lukas Foss Papers are organized in five series:
Music, circa 1926-2000
Correspondence, 1929-1999
Business Papers, 1940s-2000
Musical Works Files, 1980s-1999
Miscellany, 1940s-1999
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006579408
Container List
- Music, circa 1926-2000 (Box 1-20)
  - Orchestra, 1938-1998
    - 2 symphonic pieces, 1939-1940
      - Holograph/copyist manuscript full score (Box-folder 14/1)
      - Parts, "Overture in A" only (Box-folder 14/1)
    - 3 pieces, 1938-1939, Orchestration of Set of three pieces for two pianos
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 1/1)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 1/1)
    - American fanfare, 1990
      - Sketches (Box-folder 1/2)
    - American landscapes, 1989
      - Holograph manuscript short score (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Anniversary fanfare, 1996
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/1)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 13/1)
      - Parts (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Baroque variations. On a Bach prelude see Phorion
    - Capriccio (cello, orchestra), undated
      - Holograph manuscript full score, In caption: Arranged for cello and orchestra for Yo-Yo Ma (Box-folder 1/5)
      - Orchestral parts (Box-folder 1/5)
      - Cello part, 1946 part from version for cello and piano (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Celebration: for brass quintet and orchestra, 1998
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 1/6)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Cello concert, 1966
      - Photocopied printed full score, Annotations; In caption: For Mstislav Rostropovich (Box-folder 14/2)
      - Sketches and notes, Annotations (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Concerto for clarinet and orchestra no. 1, 1942
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 2/1)
      - Holograph manuscript short score (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Clarinet part (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Concerto for clarinet and orchestra no. 2, 1988 see also Tashi (clarinet, piano quintet), Large-scale orchestration of Tashi
      - Holograph manuscript piano-clarinet score, In caption: For rehearsal only (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Concerto for piano and orchestra no. 2, 1949-1951
      - Holograph manuscript full score, Pages 1-19 of first movement are missing (Box-folder 13/2-3)
    - Concerto for solo percussion and orchestra, 1973-1974
      - Holograph manuscript score, On title page: Revised (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Sketches and notes (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Dissertation see Exeunt
    - Elegy (clarinet, orchestra), 1949
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Elegy for Anne Frank, 1989 see also Symphony no. 3
      - 2 holograph manuscript full scores (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Parts (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Embros, 1984-1985 see also Left hand piano concerto
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 20/1)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Exeunt, 1980-1982 see also Night music for John Lennon, Early title: Dissertation
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 14/3)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Fanfare, 1973
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 2/8)
      - Sketches, notes, and program notes (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Folksong, 1975-1976
      - Sketches (Box-folder 3/1)
    - For 200 cellos, 1982-1983
      - Parts, Standard and tabulature notation (Box-folder 15/1)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 15/1)
    - For Lenny (piano, orchestra), 1988
      - Sketches (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Piano part (Box-folder 3/2)
    - For Toru, 1996
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Geod, 1969
      - Holograph manuscript score, Incomplete (Box-folder 15/2)
      - Sketches and notes (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Left hand piano concerto, 1991-1993 see also Embros, Last movement is based on Embros
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 15/3)
      - Holograph manuscript short score (Box-folder 3/4)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 3/5, 15/4)
    - Night music for John Lennon, 1980-1981
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 3/6)
      - Sketches, Includes sketches for Exeunt (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Orpheus, 1972
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 15/5)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 15/5)
      - Viola, cello, and guitar parts (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Orpheus and Euridice, 1983
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 3/8)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Phorion, 1967, Other title: Baroque variations. On a Bach prelude
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 19/1)
      - Sketches and notes (Box-folder 19/2)
      - Parts (Box-folder 19/3)
    - The prairie. Symphonic suite, 1942
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 15/6)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 15/7)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Quintets for orchestra, 1978
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/4)
      - Photocopied holograph full manuscript score, Annotations (Box-folder 13/4)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Renaissance concerto, 1985-1986
      - Holograph manuscript short score, Laid in: program notes (Box-folder 4/1)
      - Sketches and source materials (Box-folder 4/2-3)
    - Salomon Rossi suite, 1975
      - Holograph manuscript score, Introduction for brass instruments only (Box-folder 4/4)
      - Sketch, Introduction for brass instruments only (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Symphony no. 3 (Symphony of sorrows), 1991 see also Elegy for Anne Frank, Second movement is Elegy for Anne Frank
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/6)
      - Holograph manuscript short score, First and third movements only (Box-folder 4/5)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Symphony no. 4 (Windows to the past), 1995
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 16/1)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Symphony of chorales, 1958
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Three American pieces, 1986 see also Three pieces (violin, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript full score, "Early song" and "Dedication" only (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Dramatic, 1931-1949
    - Amphytrion, 1935-1936
      - Sketches (Box-folder 4/7-8)
    - The heart remembers, 1944
      - Sketches, Includes sketches for Within these walls (Box-folder 5/1)
    - The jumping frog of Calaveras County, 1949
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, Annotations (Box-folder 13/8)
    - The tempest, 1940
      - Holograph/copyist manuscript full score, Incomplete; Laid in: performance notes (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Teufelchens Geburtstag, 1931
      - Sketches, Portions are in the hand of Foss' mother; Story used as the basis for Griffelkin (Box-folder 5/3-4)
    - Untitled opera, 1933-1934?
      - Sketches (Box-folder 5/5)
    - We're with you, 1941
      - Parts, Song written for Fordham University musical (Box-folder 5/6)
      - Script (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Within these walls, 1944 see also The heart remembers
      - Typescript scenario (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Vocal, 1926-1999
    - 2 Rilke motets (voices), 1946
      - Holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 6/1)
    - 6 patriotic songs (voice, piano), 1943, Titles: We're out to win; Freedom of the seas; Banner of liberty; The people's song; Song of the United Nations; This is war
      - Holograph manuscript scores, On cover of "Banner of liberty": Louis Foster, pseudonym for Lukas Foss (Box-folder 6/2)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript scores, "This is war" is missing (Box-folder 6/2)
    - American cantata (voices, speakers, double chorus, orchestra), 1976 see also Romance
      - Sketches, correspondence, and lyric sheets (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Bunker Hill (voices, trumpets, percussion), undated
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/4)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Celebration (chorus, band or orchestra), 1996
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Congratulations (voice, piano), 1996, For Joe Maclis' ninetieth birthday
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/5)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/5)
    - De profundis (chorus), 1983
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/6)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/6)
    - For Julian's 10th anniversary at Marsh Chapel (voices), 1999
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/7)
    - For Toru: a choral opening, 1990, For Toru Takemitsu's 60th birthday
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/8)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Fragments of Archilochos (speakers, voice, choruses, instrumental ensemble), 1965
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/9)
    - I speak, I tell you (chorus), 1941, Based on text from "Prairie" by Carl Sandburg
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/10)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Kafka Tagebuch (voice), 1990-1993
      - Part (Box-folder 13/10)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Lamdeni (Teach me) (chorus, instrumental ensemble), 1973
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/11)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Measure for measure (voice, orchestra), 1980, Based on the Salomon Rossi suite
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Motette: Der bist so gross (voices), undated, Text by Rainer Maria Rilke
      - Holograph manuscript score, Incomplete (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Nachtleid (voice, piano), circa 1933
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Nachtleid (voice, orchestra), 1937
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 6/15)
    - O Herr, gib jedem seinen eignen Tod (voices), circa 1926-1938, Text by Rainer Maria Rilke
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 6/16)
    - The prairie (voices, chorus, orchestra), 1942-1943
      - Sketches (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Romance (voice, violin, string orchestra), 1994 see also American cantata, Based on the third movement of the American Cantata
      - Holograph manuscript score, In caption: For Edna Michell and Yehudi Menuhin (Box-folder 13/11)
      - Parts (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Sanctus (chorus, orchestra), 1992
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 17/1)
      - Holograph manuscript short score (Box-folder 17/1)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Die Teilung der Erde (voice, piano), 1937
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Sketches for orchestration (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Tell this blood (chorus), 1945
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Thirteen ways of looking at a blackbird (voice, flute, piano, percussion), 1978
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 7/4)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Three airs for Frank O'Hara's angel (speaker, voice, women's chorus, instrumental ensemble, tape), 1972
      - Holograph manuscript score, In caption: 1st version (Box-folder 17/2)
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Three airs for Frank O'Hara's angel (voice, flute, piano, percussion, tape), 1974-1975
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Three songs on texts by Goethe (voice, piano), 1938
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/6)
    - With music strong (chorus, orchestra), 1998
      - Holograph manuscript/photocopied full score, Incomplete; Photocopied portions have annotations (Box-folder 17/3)
      - Holograph manuscript short score, Choral section only (Box-folder 17/3)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Chamber and Solo Instrumental, 1930s-2000
    - 3 pieces (clarinet, violin, viola, cello), 1939
      - Holograph manuscript score, In caption: This piece used for the clarinet concerto (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Parts (Box-folder 7/7)
    - 4 etudes for organ, 1967
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, Laid in: performance instructions and correspondence (Box-folder 7/8)
    - 4 piano pieces, 1937
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Air (violin, piano), 1938
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Anne Frank: a brief tone poem about her life and death (cello, piano), 1999
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/11)
      - Sketches, Includes sketches for "Rondo" from Tashi (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Anniversary fanfare (brass, percussion), 1997
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/12)
      - Holograph manuscript score, Alternate version for band (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Appalachian birthday portrait (instrumental ensemble), undated, Happy birthday, written in Copland's style for Serge Koussevitzky
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, In caption: By Aaron Foss (at the piano: Lukas Copland) (Box-folder 7/13)
      - Parts (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Capriccio (cello, piano), 1946 see Capriccio (cello, orchestra)
    - The cave of the winds (wind quintet), 1972
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Central Park reel (violin, piano), 1987
      - Sketches (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Chaconne (guitar), 1987
      - Sketches (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Chamber music (tape), 1970-1973
      - Holograph manuscript score, Laid in: program notes (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Composer's nightmare (violin), 1941
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Sketch (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Conductor's nightmare (violins, piano), undated
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/5)
      - Violin parts (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Curriculum vitae (accordion), 1977
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/6)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 8/6)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, Annotations (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Curriculum vitae. Tango (piano), undated
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Curriculum vitae with time bomb (accordion, percussion), 1980
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Divertissement pour Mica (String quartet no. 2), 1973
      - Sketches (Box-folder 13/13)
    - Duo (cello, piano), 1941
      - Sketches (Box-folder 8/8)
      - Cello part (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Echoi (instrumental ensemble), 1961-1963